<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_0">Lorenz Plot Analysis Report</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_1_00">HRV data is insufficient and relevant analyses cannot be carried out. Please keep on the wearing it or wear it correctly. The longer time you wear, the more reliable the analysis results would be.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_2_11">The maximum change in heart rate during the measurement is normal and the range of heart rate change is normal.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_2_12">The maximum change in heart rate during the measurement is normal and the range of heart rate change is relatively low. Generally ,the range of nocturnal heart rate change of the population with good physical fitness and good sleeping habits will be lower, but there is a small probability of bradycardia. No special treatment is required but observation if there is no any discomfort.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_2_13">The maximum change in heart rate during the measurement is normal and the range of heart rate change is relatively high. The risk of tachyarrhythmia is relatively high and it\'s usually caused by drinking, heavy physical labor or agitation. No special treatment is required but observation if there is no any discomfort.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_2_21">The maximum change in heart rate during the measurement is relatively narrow and the range of heart rate change is normal. It\'s usually arrhythmia caused by excessive fatigue or drinking. Pay attention to alternation between work and rest and improve the sleep quality. No special treatment is required but observation if there is no any discomfort.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_2_22">The maximum change in heart rate during the measurement is relatively narrow and the range of heart rate change is relatively low. It\'s usually caused by anxiety or insomnia. No special treatment is required but observation if there is no any discomfort. There is small risk of anemia or dyspnea. It\'s advised to sleep with high pillow, stop smoking and drinking, keep mental balance and ensure enough sleep.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_2_23">The maximum change in heart rate during the measurement is relatively narrow and the range of heart rate change is relatively high. Pay attention to alternation between work and rest, avoid staying up late and ensure enough sleep if the symptom is observed on a short-term basis. Relevant physical examination is advised if the symptom is found on a long-term basis with accompanying of chest pain, palpitation, shortness of breath (mostly are myocardial ischemia).</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_2_31">The maximum change in heart rate during the measurement is relatively wide and the range of heart rate change is normal. It\'s usually caused by staying up late and insomnia. It is advised to form a good sleep habit, and do some activities that are helpful for sleeping, such as massage, foot soaking, etc.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_2_32">The maximum change in heart rate during the measurement is relatively wide and the range of heart rate change is relatively low. It\'s usually caused by bradycardia and symptoms including dizziness, transient amaurosis, acratia, palpitation, chest distress and shortness of breath can be observed. Syncope can even be found in serious cases. It\'s advised to visit the hospital for timely treatment.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_2_34">Extremely low heart rate is usually caused by wearing abnormality and it\'s advised to peruse the instructions for correct bracelet wearing. </string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_2_33">The maximum change in heart rate during the measurement is relatively wide and the range of heart rate change is relatively high. It\'s usually caused by sleep insufficiency and staying up late. Ensure the sleep and do not do activities that can easily lead to nervous and excitement before sleep. There is relatively high risk of arrhythmia and it\'s advised to culture good sleep habits, stop smoking and drinking. See a doctor as early as possible if the symptoms are not improved.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_2_35">Extremely high heart rate is usually caused by wearing abnormality and it\'s advised to peruse the instructions for correct bracelet wearing.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_3_21">There are relatively low risks of palpitation, chest distress, dyspnea, etc. when the maximum sudden change of heart rate is found at relatively high heart rate with normal degree of change. It\'s usually caused by respiratory tract obstruction or snoring. Please visit the hospital for timely treatment if any discomfort is felt. </string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_3_11">The maximum sudden change of heart rate is found at normal range with normal degree of change.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_3_31">There are relatively high risks of palpitation, chest distress, dyspnea, etc. when the maximum sudden change of heart rate is found at extremely high heart rate with normal degree of change. It\'s usually caused by influenza or fever. Please visit the hospital for timely treatment if any discomfort is felt.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_3_22">The maximum sudden change of heart rate is found at relatively high heart rate with relatively low degree of change. It\'s usually caused by dry air or sultriness in the room and it\'s advised to open the window for ventilation and pay attention to the keep warm to avoid getting cold.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_3_12">The maximum sudden change of heart rate is found at normal range with relatively low degree of change. It\'s usually caused by fatigue. No special treatment is required but observation if there is no any discomfort. Please have a good rest.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_3_32">There are mild risks of palpitation, chest distress, dyspnea, etc. when the maximum sudden change of heart rate is found at extremely high heart rate with low degree of change. It\'s usually caused by influenza, fever or agitation. There is relatively small probability of anemia. Please visit the hospital for timely treatment if any discomfort is felt.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_3_23">There are relatively high risks of palpitation, chest distress, dyspnea, etc. when the maximum sudden change of heart rate is found at relatively high heart rate with high degree of change. It\'s usually caused by supertension or agitation. Please visit the hospital for timely treatment if the symptom is found frequently and significant discomfort is felt.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_3_13">There are relatively high risks of premature beats when the maximum sudden change of heart rate is found at normal range with relatively high degree of change. No special treatment is required but observation if there is no any discomfort. It\'s advised to keep relax and relieve the tension.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_3_14">It is usually caused by wearing abnormality when the maximum sudden change of heart rate is found at normal range with abnormally high degree of change and it\'s advised to peruse the instructions for correct bracelet wearing.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_3_33">There are relatively high risks of palpitation, chest distress, dyspnea, etc. when the maximum sudden change of heart rate is found at extremely high heart rate with high degree of change. It\'s usually caused by premature beat or hypertension. Please visit the hospital for timely treatment if the symptom is found frequently with accompanying of insomnia and significant discomfort is felt.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_3_34">It is usually caused by wearing abnormality when the maximum sudden change of heart rate is found at extremely high heart rate with relatively high degree of change and it\'s advised to peruse the instructions for correct bracelet wearing.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_4_11">There is mild premature beat and it\'s usually caused by agitation, excessive smoking or drinking, etc. It\'s advised to adjust the mentality, reduce or avoid smoking and drinking.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_4_12">Cardiac stress capability weakening and moderate nervous excitation are usually caused by agitation or excitation. Acratia or tiredness in daytime can be easily caused. It\'s advised to take proper exercise before sleep to release the energy and calm down.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_4_13">Relatively weak cardiac stress capability and excessive nervous excitation are found. It\'s advised to avoid excessive excitation or nervous before sleep and a series of sleep aiding activities can be done to relieve the mood. Drinking of coffee, strong tea or wine, etc. shall be avoided recently.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_4_14">The cardiac stress capability is relatively strong. No special treatment is required but observation and exercise can be strengthened properly if fatigue or acratia is felt frequently.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_4_15">The cardiac stress capability and the metal state are both good.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_4_16">The cardiac stress capability is good and mild nervous excitation is found. Pay attention to appropriate relaxation and the alternation between work and rest before sleep.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_4_17">The cardiac stress capability is relatively strong and the neural activity is low. It\'s usually caused by excessive fatigue. Have a good rest and avoid working for long hours or staying up late recently if there is no any discomfort.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_4_18">The cardiac stress capability is good and the neural activity is relatively low. It\'s usually caused by mild fatigue. Have a good rest if there is no any discomfort.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_4_19">Mild weakening is shown in the cardiac stress capability and the neural activity is relatively low. It\'s usually caused by moderate fatigue. Have a good rest and pay attention to the alteration between work and rest.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_4_21">There is mild risk of premature beat and it can be found in normal people (agitation, nervous, fatigue, dyspepsia, excessive smoking, wine or concentrated tea drinking, etc.). Long-term observation is advised if there is no any discomfort.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_4_22">There is relatively significant premature beat and it can be observed in normal people (agitation, nervous, fatigue, dyspepsia, excessive smoking, wine or concentrated tea drinking, etc.). The symptom is more easy to be found in patient with organic heart disease and relevant physical examinations are advised.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_4_23">There is relatively high risk of premature beat and it can be found in normal people (agitation, nervous, fatigue, dyspepsia, excessive smoking, wine or concentrated tea drinking, etc.). Long-term observation is advised and relevant physical examinations shall be done as soon as possible if the symptom is found often.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_4_30">The phenomenon is not analyzed temporarily and there is small probability that relatively complicated figure can be shown in Lorenz Plot. Long-term wearing and observation are advised.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_5_11">The nocturnal heart rhythm is stable and the heart condition is good.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_5_12">The nocturnal heart rhythm is stable and the heart condition is not good. There is relatively low risk of tachycardia and excessive fatigue shall be avoided.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_5_13">The nocturnal heart rhythm is relatively stable and the heart is slightly fatigue. Avoid staying up late and ensure the sleep so that the increase of burden on the heart can be avoided.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_5_14">The nocturnal heart rhythm is relatively stable and the heart burden is relatively large. It\'s advised to reduce the oily food and keep on doing exercise.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_5_21">Arrhythmia at night with relatively large heart burden is found. Improper diet and overeating shall be avoided. Eat more fruit and vegetable and avoid catching cold.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_5_22">The nocturnal heart rhythm is relatively stable and the heart is relatively fatigue. There is relatively high risk of myocardial ischemia. It\'s advised to keep a low-salt and low-fat bland diet, stabilize the mood and avoid extreme emotions. Regular physical examination shall be implemented if there are symptoms including chest distress, palpitation, etc. </string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_5_23">The nocturnal heart rhythm is relatively stable and the heart burden is relatively large. There is relatively high risk of tachycardia. Avoid excessive fatigue, quit smoking, drink less wine and avoid excessive physical labor or sudden power exertion.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_5_24">Arrhythmia at night with slightly fatigue heart is found. There is relatively low risk of myocardial ischemia. Physical examination shall be received regularly if there is no any discomfort. It\'s advised to visit the hospital for timely treatment if fatigue, acratia and poor mental state accompanied by chest distress or shortness of breath, etc. are found.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_5_25">The nocturnal heart rhythm is relatively stable and the heart burden is relatively large. The risks of hyperlipoidemia and hypertension are increasing. It\'s advised to keep a bland diet and avoid excessive drinking. Receive physical examination regularly and appropriate weight losing is advised for obese people.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_5_26">Arrhythmia at night with relatively fatigue heart is found. There are risks of dyspnea and insufficient blood supply. It\'s advised to sleep sideway, increase properly the air humidity in the room, strengthen the exercise, avoid agitation and excessive fatigue. Receive physical examination regularly and attach importance to the blood pressure monitoring.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_5_31">Arrhythmia at night with relatively large heart burden is found and there is sinus tachycardia symptom. It\'s usually caused by drinking of coffee or strong tea or doing activities that can lead to nervous or exciting emotions before sleep. It can also be resulted from diseases such as fever, anemia, hyperthyroidism, etc. Good life pattern shall be developed and physical examination shall be done regularly. See a doctor in time if there is any discomfort.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_5_32">Arrhythmia at night with relatively fatigue heart is found and there is bradycardia symptom. It\'s usually caused by anemia, myocarditis or myocardial infarction. It can also be resulted from the relatively low temperature at the measuring part. Pay attention to the keep warm and have a long-term observation. Physical examination and timely treatment are advised if the symptom is observed frequently with accompanying of depression, acratia and dizziness.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_5_33">Arrhythmia at night with relatively large heart burden is found. Mental stress, heavy smoking, drinking of wine, strong tea or coffee, excessive fatigue, serious insomnia, etc. are usually the inducement factors for arrhythmia. It\'s advised to develop a good life pattern, balance the work and rest and receive regular physical examination.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_5_40">The phenomenon is not analyzed temporarily and there is small probability that relatively complicated figure can be shown in Lorenz Plot. Long-term wearing and observation are advised.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_2">Heart rate change</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_3">Sudden change of heart rate</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_4">Neural state</string>
    <string name="vphrv_repo_5">Heart rhythm change</string>

    <string name="vphrv_lorentz_chart">Lorentz scatter diagram</string>
    <string name="vphrv_lorentz_chart_1">Comet</string>
    <string name="vphrv_lorentz_chart_2">Rocket</string>
    <string name="vphrv_lorentz_chart_3">Shuttle</string>
    <string name="vphrv_lorentz_chart_4">Baton</string>
    <string name="vphrv_lorentz_chart_5">Grenade</string>
    <string name="vphrv_lorentz_chart_6">Fork</string>
    <string name="vphrv_lorentz_chart_7">Stub</string>
    <string name="vphrv_lorentz_chart_8">Rice</string>
    <string name="vphrv_lorentz_chart_9">Torpedo</string>
    <string name="vphrv_lorentz_chart_des_1">Common form with normal adults, symmetrical spreading at 45° from narrow head, in comet shape, not obvious narrow head with some group of people, zone of scatted points in big spacing of points or dense points in the tail, slim sharp corner, normal phenomenon</string>
    <string name="vphrv_lorentz_chart_des_2">Bulky, small head and big tail, dense and sharp head, symmetrical spreading at 45° from head and gradually widening, gradual widening of spacing between points to the tail, common among snoring people or people with apnea syndrome, bigger spacing between points with worse condition</string>
    <string name="vphrv_lorentz_chart_des_3">Small on both ends, wide in middle part, like a shuttle, common among patients of minor myocardial ischemia, incident of small probability among normal people</string>
    <string name="vphrv_lorentz_chart_des_4">Slim, small head, basically consistent in form from middle part to tail, most common among patients with coronary heart disease</string>
    <string name="vphrv_lorentz_chart_des_5">Like grenade, wide head and tail, slim in middle part, usually wider tail than head, most common among patients with atrial fibrillation, and likely to occur with frequent palpitation</string>
    <string name="vphrv_lorentz_chart_des_6">Main dense zones like miniaturized comet, sharp head, pork-like tail with scattered points, common among CHF patients</string>
    <string name="vphrv_lorentz_chart_des_7">Look like miniaturized comet, small head and big tail, in small area, common among people with large cardiac load, cardiac failure in worsened condition, incident with normal people after drinking or fatigue</string>
    <string name="vphrv_lorentz_chart_des_8">Very short and small, basically consistent head and tail, like rice, common among patients with arrhythmia, PVT in most cases</string>
    <string name="vphrv_lorentz_chart_des_9">Short, slightly bigger tip, tail of constant width as a rod; common in patient with nodal tachycardia, usually caused by physiological factors like agitated sentiment or drinking strong tea or coffee, or by illnesses such as cold, fever, anemia or hyperthyreosis; small probability incident with average healthy person.</string>
    <string name="vphrv_lorentz_chart_refer">Reference of Lorentz scatter diagram</string>

</resources>
